Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And my name is Catherine.
我是Catherine。
And today we're going to be visiting one of my favorite places, I must say.
今天我们要去一个我最喜欢的地方，我得说。
Really?
真的吗？
So you're a big meat eater?
所以你是个爱吃肉的人？
I am.
是的。
I have to have meat every day, so that's why I usually go to the butcher.
我每天都必须吃肉，所以通常我会去肉店。
All right.
好的。
So vegetarians be warned, today's dialogue is all about eating meat and where to go to
所以素食者们注意了，今天的对话全是关于吃肉和去哪里
get meat.
买肉。
So as Marco said, that place is called the butcher's.
就像Marco说的，那个地方叫肉店。
So we're going to be visiting the butcher and we're going to learn all the different
所以我们要去肉店，学习所有不同的
types of meat you can find there.
你能在那里找到的肉类种类。
Great.
太好了。
So we don't have anything to preview, but before we get started, just like to mention
我们没什么要预览的，但在开始之前，我想提一下
that you're going to hear a lot of different kinds of words and we'll be back in a minute
你会听到很多不同的单词，我们一会儿回来
to talk about what they mean.
讨论它们的意思。
Hi, what can I get for you?
你好，需要点什么？
I'd like half pound of ground beef, please.
我想要半磅碎牛肉，谢谢。
Good choice.
好选择。
Our ground beef is extra lean, if you know what I mean.
我们的碎牛肉是超瘦的，你懂的。
Could I also have half a dozen pork chops and two pounds of boneless chicken breast?
我还能要半打猪排和两磅无骨鸡胸肉吗？
No, no, no chicken breasts at the moment.
不，不，不，现在没有鸡胸肉。
But we have some nice chicken thighs.
但我们有一些不错的鸡大腿。
No, that won't do.
不，那不行。
I'll take this smoked ham you have here.
我要你这里的这块烟熏火腿。
Sorry, is there anything else?
抱歉，还要别的吗？
Is this salami and bologna you have here?
这是你这里的萨拉米和博洛尼亚香肠吗？
Yes, it's very fine meat.
是的，这是非常好的肉。
Made it myself.
我自己做的。
Sounds good.
听起来不错。
Okay, that's it.
好的，就这些了。
Wait, we have T-bone, rib eye and sirloin steaks.
等等，我们有T骨、肋眼和西冷牛排。
They are very fresh.
它们非常新鲜。
Just came from the slaughterhouse.
刚从屠宰场来的。
No, that's okay.
不，不用了。
Really, I think that's all for today.
真的，我想今天就这些了。
Okay, that'll be $34.50.
好的，总共34.50美元。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So this butcher was kind of creepy in the beginning.
所以这个屠夫一开始有点吓人。
Very creepy in the beginning.
一开始非常吓人。
I think that's usually the conception that you have of butchers because they always have
我觉得这通常是人们对屠夫的印象，因为他们总是拿着
a knife and they're always covered in blood, but it's not human blood.
一把刀，而且浑身是血，但那是动物的血，不是人血。
Right, like the movie Sweeney Todd.
对，就像电影《理发师陶德》里那样。
Did you see that?
你看过那部电影吗？
Yeah, like Sweeney Todd.
嗯，就像《理发师陶德》。
The butcher of Fleet Street.
舰队街的屠夫。
But we actually took a look at a lot of different types of meat that the woman was ordering.
但我们实际上仔细看了看那位女士订购的各种肉类。
So why don't we take a look at these now in Language Takeaway.
那么，我们现在就在“语言小贴士”环节来看看这些吧。
Language Takeaway.
语言小贴士。
Okay, so the first is a classic cut.
好的，第一个是经典切块。
This is something that we had at my house about once a week growing up.
这是我小时候家里每周大约吃一次的东西。
It's called a pork chop.
它叫做猪排。
Pork chop.
猪排。
So a pork chop comes from the animal, the pork or pig.
所以猪排来自动物，也就是猪。
Yeah, we actually don't say pork to mean the animal.
是的，我们实际上不说“pork”来指代动物。
Pork just means the kind of meat that comes from a pig.
“Pork”只是指来自猪的肉。
So big difference there when we're talking about food, we say pork.
所以当我们谈论食物时，有很大区别，我们说“pork”。
Oh, wow.
哦，哇。
And what about a pork chop?
那猪排呢？
So what exactly is that?
它到底是什么？
Chop is usually just on the bone and oftentimes it's fried or baked, I guess, but it's just
“Chop”通常指带骨的肉，而且经常是煎或烤的，我想，但它就是
a piece of pork on the bone and a chop, you just imagine a knife chopping something.
一块带骨的猪肉，“chop”这个词，你想象一下用刀砍东西。
All right, so a pork chop, very good.
好了，所以猪排，非常好。
And after pork chops, we were ordering some ground beef.
猪排之后，我们点了一些碎牛肉。
All right, so ground beef is another important one.
好的，碎牛肉是另一个重要的东西。
Ground beef is beef that's been chopped up and pushed through a machine that kind of
碎牛肉是把牛肉切碎，然后通过一台机器，
pushes it out in very, very small bits and pieces.
把它压成非常非常小的碎块。
There's no bones.
没有骨头。
So ground comes from the verb to grind.
所以“ground”来自动词“grind”。
So to grind up meat, to make it very, very small pieces.
就是把肉磨碎，弄成非常小的碎块。
Right, so if you want to make a spaghetti bolognese, the kind of beef you use is ground
对，所以如果你想做意大利肉酱面，用的牛肉就是碎牛肉，
beef or even hamburgers.
或者做汉堡包也用。
Oh, yeah, exactly.
哦，是的，没错。
So ground beef, you ground up beef.
所以碎牛肉，就是把牛肉磨碎。
What other things would you grind?
还有什么东西可以磨碎？
You could grind your teeth.
你可以磨牙。
Some people do that when they're sleeping, they grind their teeth.
有些人睡觉时会磨牙。
You can grind, you have pepper grinders.
你可以磨，比如有胡椒研磨器。
You know, peppers sometimes come in balls and you have to grind them to make them smaller
你知道，辣椒有时候是球状的，你得把它们磨碎才能变小。
and broken down.
并且弄碎。
Very good.
很好。
So that's ground beef and from the verb to grind.
所以那就是碎牛肉，来自动词“grind”。
Now we are buying some boneless chicken breasts.
现在我们买一些去骨鸡胸肉。
All right, so boneless, as you have guessed, means without bones.
好的，所以“boneless”，正如你猜到的，意思是“没有骨头”。
And chicken breasts are usually just a really nice, juicy, kind of tender cut of meat from
鸡胸肉通常是一块非常棒、多汁、比较嫩的肉，来自
the chicken, from the underside of the chicken where obviously, yeah, they have it.
鸡的下面部位，显然，那里就是长鸡胸肉的地方。
It's not a wing, it's not a leg, it's just a chicken breast.
它不是翅膀，不是腿，就是鸡胸肉。
All right, so boneless chicken breast.
好的，所以是去骨鸡胸肉。
Now usually it is boneless, right, when you buy it at the supermarket.
通常超市里买到的都是去骨的，对吧？
Yeah, yeah.
嗯，对。
Next up, we've got some classic deli counter favorites.
接下来，我们有一些经典的熟食柜台最爱。
These are our cold cuts.
这些是我们的冷切肉。
All right, so cold cuts.
好的，所以是冷切肉。
Now this means that they are cold?
这是说它们是冷的吗？
Oh, well, yeah, they're cold.
哦，嗯，对，它们是冷的。
But I think cold cuts, the most important thing to remember here is that they're mostly
但我觉得冷切肉，这里要记住的最重要一点是它们大多是
like kinds of salami or cured meats.
像萨拉米或腌制肉类。
So these are salt cured or they're dried meats.
所以这些是盐腌或风干的肉。
And you usually have them on sandwiches, so like a salami sandwich.
你通常把它们放在三明治里，比如萨拉米三明治。
So like cured meat, you mean that meat hasn't been cooked?
所以像腌制肉，你是说肉没有煮熟？
Oh, no, it's not been cooked, but it's treated in a way that allows it to last for a very
哦，不，它没被煮过，但用一种方式处理过，让它能保存很
long time.
长时间。
So they look like long, long tubes of meat.
所以它们看起来像长长的肉管。
They look very dry.
看起来很干。
They look very dry, like beef jerky, for example.
看起来很干，比如像牛肉干。
All right, so cured meat.
好的，所以是腌制肉。
Now, for example, we have salami and bologna.
现在，比如，我们有萨拉米和波洛尼亚香肠。
Bologna.
波洛尼亚香肠。
Now, it's interesting because bologna is actually spelled B-O-L-O-G-N-A.
有趣的是，波洛尼亚香肠实际上拼写为B-O-L-O-G-N-A。
So you would say bologna or something like that.
所以你会说“bologna”或类似的东西。
Well, I think it comes from the Italian bologna.
嗯，我觉得它来自意大利语的“bologna”。
But it's definitely a change that happened in the English language when it came over
但它在传入英语时确实发生了变化
from Italy.
从意大利。
But bologna is a kind of meat that's got a very funny looking name.
但波洛尼亚香肠是一种名字看起来很有趣的肉。
Yeah, see, you're more sophisticated than I am.
是啊，你看，你比我更有见识。
That's why you know this difference.
所以你知道这个区别。
I just speak Italian.
我只是会说意大利语。
All right, so you have salami, bologna, and...
好的，所以你有萨拉米、波洛尼亚香肠，还有……
Pastrami.
五香熏牛肉。
What about ham?
那火腿呢？
Is that considered a cold cut?
那算冷切肉吗？
You can have ham in the cold cut section because ham sometimes comes in tubes that you slice.
火腿可以放在冷切肉区，因为火腿有时是管状的，需要切片。
But ham is also just a normal kind of pork.
但火腿也是一种普通的猪肉。
But ham is cured, you know.
不过火腿是腌制的，你知道的。
Like a smoked ham.
比如烟熏火腿。
Exactly.
没错。
Or smoked turkey, one of my favorites.
或者烟熏火鸡，我最喜欢的一种。
Very good.
非常好。
And, well, now moving on from the cold cuts, we're going to concentrate on steaks.
好了，现在从冷切肉继续，我们要集中讲牛排了。
Ooh, steaks.
哦，牛排。
So there are a thousand kinds of steaks in this world and every city seems to have its
世界上有上千种牛排，每个城市似乎都有自己
own kind.
的特色。
But here we're only looking at three, the first of which is the T-bone.
但这里我们只看三种，第一种是T骨牛排。
All right, the T-bone steak, I think, is one of the most popular ones.
好的，T骨牛排，我觉得是最受欢迎的一种。
Definitely.
确实。
It's a steak that's pretty big, right?
这是一种相当大的牛排，对吧？
Yeah, well, yeah, it can be.
嗯，是的，可以这么说。
And it has a bone inside that looks like a T.
而且里面有一块骨头，看起来像字母T。
All right, so you're saying, Marco, that the T-bone is named after the shape and the look
好的，所以你是说，Marco，T骨牛排是根据形状和外观
of this steak.
命名的。
Yeah, T-bone steak.
是的，T骨牛排。
All right.
好的。
And as well as our next one is also a rib eye.
还有我们的下一种也是肋眼牛排。
Okay, so the rib eye, I think, actually has a piece of the rib in it.
好的，肋眼牛排，我觉得实际上带有一块肋骨。
So the rib is the bone and there's a circle, which is kind of a, it's, it's a, the piece
所以肋骨就是骨头，还有一个圆圈，那是一种，它是，它是，那块
of meat is sliced off the rib and the circle is actually part of that rib.
肉是从肋骨上切下来的，那个圆圈实际上是肋骨的一部分。
So there's a little bit of bone in it.
所以里面有一点骨头。
But it's not as bony as the T-bone.
但它不像T骨牛排那么骨多。
Right.
对。
So it does have one small bone that kind of looks like an eye because you can see through
所以它确实有一小块骨头，看起来有点像眼睛，因为你可以看穿
it.
它。
And our next steak has no bone and is the most tender and the best steak you can have,
而我们下一种牛排没有骨头，是最嫩、最好的牛排，
sirloin steak.
西冷牛排。
So I think the, the sirloin is definitely the most expensive if you're in a restaurant.
所以我觉得，西冷牛排绝对是餐厅里最贵的。
Definitely the most tender, I think, of all those.
绝对是所有里面最嫩的，我觉得。
It's delicious.
很好吃。
And usually you can have like a big sirloin steak, like a half a kilo, like a 400 gram
而且通常你可以吃一大块西冷牛排，比如半公斤，像400克
sirloin steak.
的西冷牛排。
I had a friend who ate a full kilo.
我有个朋友吃了一整公斤。
Really?
真的吗？
Sirloin steak.
西冷牛排。
Wow.
哇。
Is there a competition or?
是有比赛吗？
No, there's a kind of steak called la bistecca alla fiorentina in Italy.
不，在意大利有一种牛排叫la bistecca alla fiorentina。
It's the Florentine beef steak and it is, it can be about a kilo of meat.
那是佛罗伦萨牛排，它可能有一公斤重。
Wow.
哇。
Yeah.
是啊。
I bet you can't even move after that.
我打赌吃完后你动都动不了。
No, you're, no, you fall asleep with your head in your soup on the table.
不，你会，不，你会头埋在桌上的汤里睡着。
All right.
好的。
So that's all the meat related words that we have for you today.
这就是我们今天为你准备的所有与肉类相关的词汇。
So why don't we move on now to Fluency Builder where we're going to take a look at some of
那么我们现在进入流利度训练环节，看看这个对话中的一些
the phrases in this dialogue.
短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度训练。
We're going to look at the phrases if you know what I mean.
我们要看这些短语，如果你懂我的意思。
If you know what I mean.
如果你懂我的意思。
Now I love this phrase, if you know what I mean.
我喜欢这个短语，如果你懂我的意思。
I do know what you mean.
我懂你的意思。
Well, it's weird.
嗯，这有点奇怪。
I like it too.
我也喜欢它。
So you can use it for sarcasm.
你可以用它来表示讽刺。
Yeah.
是的。
Right.
对。
Or you can use it to kind of insinuate something.
或者你可以用它来暗示某事。
Right.
对。
Exactly.
没错。
Yeah.
是的。
So here's what you're saying.
所以这就是你要说的。
You're saying there's a double meaning in what I want to say.
你是说我想说的话有双重含义。
So there's two things I could say and I'm not going to say it outright, but you know,
所以有两件事我可以说，但我不会直接说出来，但你知道，
this thing that we can't really say.
这件我们不能明说的事。
So for example, we can say she likes to go out if you know what I mean.
比如，我们可以说，她喜欢出去玩，如果你懂我的意思。
All right.
好的。
So you're insinuating that not only does she like to go out, but maybe, maybe she goes
所以你在暗示她不仅喜欢出去玩，而且可能，可能她出去
out a lot, a lot, or maybe she gets drunk or something like that.
很多很多次，或者她喝醉了之类的。
Yeah.
是的。
So it's kind of like a double meaning, but you're trying to be subtle.
所以这有点像双重含义，但你想表达得含蓄。
Yeah.
是的。
But it's not so subtle because you're actually saying like, this is not what I mean.
但也不那么含蓄，因为你实际上在说，这不是我的意思。
Or she's eating for two if you know what I mean.
或者，她在为两个人吃饭，如果你懂我的意思。
There we go.
这就对了。
So you're insinuating that, well, you're not really insinuating, you're telling me that.
所以你在暗示，嗯，你其实不是在暗示，你在告诉我。
She's pregnant.
她怀孕了。
Eating for two is a common idiom in English that means that a person, a woman has a, well,
“为两个人吃饭”是英语中一个常见的习语，意思是某人，一个女人有，嗯，
is going to have a baby.
要生孩子了。
So here I'm saying, hey, do you know this idiom?
所以这里我在说，嘿，你知道这个习语吗？
She's eating for two if you know what I mean.
她在为两个人吃饭，如果你懂我的意思。
Right.
对。
Wink, wink, wink.
眨眼，眨眼，眨眼。
Wink, wink.
眨眼，眨眼。
So now why don't we take a look at some other examples of how we could use if you know what
那么现在我们来看看其他一些例子，看看在不同情况下如何用“如果你懂我的意思”
I mean in different circumstances when you're trying to insinuate something.
来暗示某事。
Example one.
例子一。
She's eating for two now, if you know what I mean.
她现在在为两个人吃饭，如果你懂我的意思。
Example two.
例子二。
Tim hit a home run today, if you know what I mean.
蒂姆今天打了一个本垒打，如果你懂我的意思。
Example three.
例子三。
Jim and Laura are going their separate ways, if you know what I mean.
吉姆和劳拉各走各的路了，如果你懂我的意思。
All right.
好的。
We're back.
我们回来了。
So now that that's clear, why don't we move on to our next phrase?
现在既然清楚了，我们进入下一个短语吧。
So this one is a counting phrase.
这是一个计数短语。
And for those of you who have heard the word dozen before, it might not be so new.
对于那些听过“打”这个词的人来说，可能并不陌生。
The phrase is half a dozen.
这个短语是“半打”。
Half a dozen.
半打。
So that means half of 12.
所以意思是12的一半。
12.
12。
So a dozen is 12.
所以一打是12。
And it's, I'm not really sure when this started being used in English, but a dozen is 12 and
我不太确定英语中什么时候开始用这个词，但一打是12，
half a dozen is then six.
半打就是6。
Now there's another phrase or another saying that's very common, a dime a dozen.
还有一个很常见的短语或说法，“一毛钱一打”。
He's a dime a dozen.
他是一毛钱一打。
So that means you can get 12 of the same type of guys for 10 cents.
意思是你可以用10美分买到12个同类型的家伙。
Right.
对。
So they're easy to find.
所以他们很容易找到。
They're easy to find.
很容易找到。
Yeah.
是的。
The dime a dozen.
这种货色多得很。
All right.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
And moving on to our last one.
接下来看最后一个。
When they were talking, they said something about the meat being lean, extra lean.
他们聊天时提到了肉是瘦的、特别瘦的。
Okay.
好的。
Lean, this does not mean lean on a door.
“Lean”不是指靠在门上。
This is not like resting on something.
不是那种依靠的意思。
This is actually a kind of way to describe food.
这其实是描述食物的一种方式。
And so food is lean if it's not got much fat, it's not fatty.
所以食物如果脂肪少、不油腻，就是瘦的。
Okay.
好的。
So if it's lean, it doesn't have much fat.
所以如果肉是瘦的，脂肪就不多。
Exactly.
没错。
So I prefer to eat lean meats.
所以我更喜欢吃瘦肉。
So I often eat birds and poultry.
所以我常吃禽类。
So chicken, I like it pretty lean.
比如鸡肉，我喜欢比较瘦的。
And if it's got fat on it, I'll cut the fat off.
如果上面有肥肉，我会切掉。
Oh, okay.
哦，好的。
Like the skin.
比如皮。
The skin is fat, right?
皮就是脂肪，对吧？
Yeah.
对。
All right.
好的。
So you can have lean beef.
所以你可以吃瘦牛肉。
It doesn't have much fat around it.
它周围没有太多肥肉。
Yeah.
对。
And actually on the packages at the supermarket, it often says the percentage of meat that
实际上超市的包装上经常标着肉的百分比，
you have.
就是含量。
So it's 95% lean or 98% lean.
比如95%瘦或98%瘦。
So that means you have 3% fat in there.
那就意味着里面有3%的脂肪。
Exactly.
没错。
Or 2%.
或者2%。
My math skills are amazing.
我的数学能力真棒。
All right.
好的。
So now that we've finished with all of these words on Fluency Builder, let's take a look
现在我们学完了“流利度构建”里的所有单词，最后再听一遍对话。
at our dialogue for the last time.
最后再听一遍对话。
Hi, what can I get for you?
您好，您要点什么？
No, no, no chicken breasts at the moment, but we have some nice chicken thighs.
不，不，现在没有鸡胸肉，但我们有一些不错的鸡大腿。
No that won't do.
那不行。
I'll take this smoked ham you have here.
我要您这儿的烟熏火腿。
Okay.
好的。
Is there anything else?
还有别的吗？
Is this salami and bologna you have here?
你这里的萨拉米和博洛尼亚香肠是吗？
Yes.
是的。
It's very fine meat.
这是上好的肉。
Made it myself.
我自己做的。
Sounds good.
听起来不错。
Okay, that's it.
好了，就这些。
Great.
太好了。
We have T-bone, rib eye, and sirloin steaks.
我们有T骨牛排、肋眼牛排和西冷牛排。
They are very fresh.
它们非常新鲜。
Just came from the slaughterhouse.
刚从屠宰场送来的。
No, that's okay, really.
不，不用了，真的。
I think that's all for today.
我想今天就要这些了。
Okay, that'll be $34.50.
好的，一共34.50美元。
Alright, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So Catherine, are you a big beef or meat eater?
那么凯瑟琳，你是个爱吃牛肉或肉食的人吗？
Definitely am.
绝对是。
It helps that my partner in crime is from Kansas City and they have the best, among
我的搭档来自堪萨斯城，这很有帮助，那里有全美国最好的牛排之一。
the best steaks in our entire country in Kansas City.
堪萨斯城的牛排是全美国最好的。
Wow.
哇。
I actually miss, there was back in California, we had the $6 burger from Carl's Jr.
我其实挺怀念的，以前在加州，我们有卡尔汉堡的6美元汉堡。
It was just basically beef, bacon, cheese, it was just like this huge burger full of
基本上就是牛肉、培根、奶酪，就像一个巨大的汉堡，全是肉。
meat and obviously a lot of calories.
显然热量也很高。
But it was delicious.
但味道很棒。
In Ecuador we are very used to having some meat product every day with our food.
在厄瓜多尔，我们习惯每天吃饭时都搭配一些肉制品。
Yeah, well it's the same in the Midwest actually from where we're from.
是啊，其实我们中西部老家也是这样。
It's the same in the Midwest because people in the Midwest generally think that if you're
中西部也一样，因为那里的人通常觉得，如果你不吃肉，那你吃什么？
not eating meat then what are you eating?
面包？
Bread?
玉米？
Right.
对。
Corn?
所以肉被认为是日常健康饮食的一部分，你肯定会在正餐中吃它。
Yeah.
是啊，我确定我们的素食听众可能不太喜欢这个，但这只是不同的饮食习惯。
So meat is considered a healthy part of the day and you definitely eat it with your meals.
有些人，比如每天吃米饭。
Yeah, and I'm sure our vegetarian listeners might not appreciate this but it's just kind
而在其他国家，你不会每天都吃米饭。
of different diets.
或者，比如我在智利的时候，吃了很多土豆。
Some people eat, for example, rice every day.
真的吗？
So where in other countries you wouldn't really have rice every day.
很多土豆。
Or for example, when I was in Chile, I had a lot of potatoes.
是的。
Really?
所以肉被认为是日常健康饮食的一部分，你肯定会在正餐中吃它。
A lot of potatoes.
是啊，我确定我们的素食听众可能不太喜欢这个，但这只是不同的饮食习惯。
Have you ever had an Argentine steak?
你吃过阿根廷牛排吗？
I hear they have the best beef in the world.
我听说他们有世界上最好的牛肉。
They are not only delicious but they are very inexpensive and it's amazing.
它们不仅美味，而且非常便宜，简直不可思议。
You can have a complete steak buffet for like, I don't know, I can't even remember but I
你可以吃一顿完整的牛排自助餐，大概，我不知道，我甚至记不清了，但我
sat there for three hours and couldn't move and kept eating.
坐在那里吃了三个小时，动弹不得，还一直吃。
Is it true you can eat it with a spoon?
真的能用勺子吃吗？
It's so soft?
它那么嫩？
Some of the meat is very, very tender.
有些肉非常非常嫩。
Not if it's grilled, you can't really do that, but in other preparations it's almost like
如果是烤的就不行，你做不到，但其他做法几乎就像
that.
那样。
With a nice butter sauce.
配上美味的黄油酱。
Mmm, herbs.
嗯，香草。
Making me hungry.
让我饿了。
I know, you've made me hungry.
我知道，你也让我饿了。
I think we're going to take off and have some burgers.
我想我们该走了，去吃些汉堡。
If you have any questions, any comments, please come to our website at EnglishPod.com and
如果你有任何问题或评论，请访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com，
we're there to answer any doubts.
我们会在那里解答任何疑问。
And we'd love to know what your favorite foods are, meat or otherwise, so post something
我们很想知道你最喜欢的食物是什么，肉类或其他，所以请在我们的网站上
on our website.
发帖。
Hope to see you there soon.
希望很快在那里见到你。
Bye.
再见。
Cheeseputer.com